<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Gatsby Starter Blog RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[A QA blog focusing mainly on Playwright and TypeScript.]]></description><link>https://alplionqa.github.io</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 20:36:09 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Hello World - let's meet!]]></title><description><![CDATA[Hello there! Cześć! Merhaba! I got my first QA job back in July, 2018, in an indie game development studio working on in-house project…]]></description><link>https://alplionqa.github.io/hello-world/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://alplionqa.github.io/hello-world/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2025 21:37:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Hello there! Cześć! Merhaba!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got my first QA job back in July, 2018, in an indie game development studio working on in-house project called Gloria Victis: Medieval MMORPG. A huge scale project with small budget and small studio, only ~10 people, based in Lublin, Poland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my 3.5 year work there, I learnt a lot of things thanks to having access to the source code, often analysing how code behaves, so called &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;white-box testing&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at one point I realized gaming industry is not my place, at least not full time. So I have decided to become a corpo-guy. Started working with serious clients, enterprise web applications. And this is where I, for the first time, started automating tests, using &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Cypress&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was very nice start! Later I started working in various projects, where I had a hybrid role: do any kind of testing. This is when I first had an opportunity to start using &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Playwright&lt;/code&gt;. And this was exactly what we call &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;love on first sight&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later switching to full time QA Automation Engineer position, I had an opportunity to work on a test framework consisting of &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;Cucumber.js + Playwright&lt;/code&gt;. That was a hell of an experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After next 3.5 year work as corpo-guy, I again switched a job, where I continue my only normal relationship with &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;my beloved Playwright&lt;/code&gt;. This is the time period when I more or less started this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what about this blog? - &lt;em&gt;It will be for sharing my experience.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How often? - &lt;em&gt;Regularly.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What else? - &lt;em&gt;I like pitsa a lot.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With ananas? - &lt;em&gt;Hell no.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See you in another blog post :)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>